hi and welcome to living in Central
Texas now if you're relocating to the
central Texas area particularly Temple
belon Bell County and the idea of lake
living with trees roaming deer in your
front yard and just being immersed in
nature is appealing to you you'll
definitely want to watch this video as I
give you a tour of Morgan's Point Texas
morg Point Resort it's just outside of
belon Texas and it's so cute I can't
wait to show you hi I'm Andrea dudic
realtor and Associate broker with f real
estate so I'm currently in um Temple
Park Temple Lake park in Temple but it's
one of the parks that you can access
from Morgan's Point or nearest Morgan's
Point there's also Rogers Park and um
the Morgan Point Rina and just multiple
access points throughout Morgan's Point
which is really cool as you can see it's
super beautiful and believe it or not we
are end of December and it is upwards of
60° right now which I can't believe nice
and sunny and pretty so Texas weather is
absolutely all over the place it's
really sunny today but I expect to be
wearing a nice full jacket in a couple
weeks so Morgan's Point has a population
of roughly 4,000 but it's a little tiny
suburb from belon Texas in fact Morgans
Point Texas is part of belon ISD the
belon school district I'm actually
including a link below um so you can
find out all the information on belon
ISD if that's super important to you
belon is much larger um but what's
really cool about living in Morgan's
Point and PR is that you really get that
small town feel and that privacy but
you're really close to bigger amenities
and that's something I particularly love
living there I mean there are genuinely
deer walking the streets my kids think
that's so cool and just tons of
beautiful large oak trees it's just
really really pretty and as you can see
behind me lake living really awesome if
you enjoy
kaying skiing boating fishing this is a
great area for that so within Morgan's
Point we have two restaurants we have so
de halis go which is a chain there's uh
four or five of them there's quite a few
of them throughout Temple Balon and then
there's also Backyard Barbecue which is
so good and definitely worth the drive
to I think it's one of my favorites from
there they have awesome chicken fried
steak and just their classic barbecue
chicken pork sausage it's all really
great so that's a a cute little place to
go to if you live there or if you live
nearby now if you don't want those two
things um there are you can access all
of belton's amenities so belon is just
minutes away
from Morgan's Point um and so you're
probably 15 minutes away from Walmart
off of West Adams or there's also
Walmart off of 317 HB another large
grocery
store uh Starbucks summer Moon I just
did a video on summer Moon and tons of
different restaurants I mean you're
really super close to everything within
Morgan's Point you have a bunch of
different communities to live in a bunch
of different residential communities
there are still a few new construction
communities to build in if that's
something that interests you we have
logo Terra Ranch o Del logo and Cliffs
at Lake
belon um other established communities
are going to be sabron Holly Oaks and
then just more of the older residential
communities uh in there too so I
actually just did a video if you want to
check out my YouTube it is touring a
$799,000 new build by KS if you would
like to see a stunning luxury home in
Rancho Del logo and in a little bit I'll
show you Cliffs at Lake belon and we'll
take a look at a bunch of the lots that
are still for sale for you to build
custom this is the newest community in
Morgan's Point Resort The Cliffs at Lake
belon there are few Lakefront lots
available but most are inside Lots which
are still beautiful and being sold by
the developer there are over a dozen
Lots still available ranging from 125 to
155,000 and 6 to7 Acres so between a
half and 3/4 of an acre per lot the
couple of lake lots that are available
are upwards of 200 to 300,000 and are
actually resales they were sold and then
are being resold this community is at
the end of Morgans Point Road so there
is very little traffic it also runs
along Camp kacina Road and Camp cacina
is a girl scale Camp um but there's
pretty little traffic there too as you
can see there are so many trees and the
homes are gorgeous if you're looking to
build a custom home we can definitely
talk options on land loans construction
loans as well as available builders in
this area these are some of the most eye
appealing lots you'll find around so I'm
standing in front of Commonwealth it is
the newest edition in Morgan Point
Resort it's just off of West Adams in
Temple right on the temple Morgans Point
border and it is exactly what this area
needed they have a pickle ball court
which is really fun especially on a date
night you can do pickle ball go have a
specialty cocktail their cocktail menu
is fantastic they also have a really
great food menu and they're open for
brunch lunch and dinner definitely a
place to check out if you're in the
area so this is our retail business PL a
here in Morgan's Point Resort we've got
a doughnut shop that I take my little
girls to all the time they love it um
let's see Counseling Center we have a
gym right behind me the point Fitness
and what's really cool about this area
is that you have some amenities right
here that are very private secluded to
Morgan's Point but you're about 5
minutes away from the lake and 10
minutes away from shopping at Major
grocery stores Walmart HB
Starbucks all the best restaurants so
you really get the Best of Both Worlds
by being here okay so I am standing at a
really beautiful Overlook in Miller
Springs Park this is a park within
Temple it's probably 5 minutes away from
Morgan's Point super easy parking you
have over 260 Acres of park over 10
acres of trail to walk run um have
picnics with family so just another one
of the wonderful parks here to check out
in our area and super close to Morgan
Point
Resort so I'm at clus Park in Morgan's
Point this is a awesome Park
specifically designated to Morgan's
Point and honestly I would drive my kids
here even if I didn't live here so you
can see behind me the lake it's really
pretty and there's um like an older kid
side with a old old school you know old
school swings and slide and then on this
side of the park they've completely
redone it and it is amazing for little
kids so on the other side which I'll
walk over and show you it's a toddler
section for kids aged 3 to 5 and
everything there is toddler appropriate
and my girls love it and over here we
have a tennis court which is really
great too
so my girls favorite thing here is
actually the zipline I actually don't
know of another Park here that has the
zipline there's also a basketball court
picnic tables so a really great place to
have birthday parties too and then
during the summer um they actually have
a Rex center with a community pool and
you can get passes for swimming so let's
talk price point Morgan's Point is one
of the only places in our area with
condos on the water I just checked today
and I even saw some as as low as
$160,000 aside from those condos we have
older established communities and brand
new communities with new homes and new
Custom Homes so those price points might
look as low as 240,000 for a resale all
the way up to a million for your awesome
dream home so regardless whatever your
price point is if you are looking to
live in Morgan's Point I'm sure we can
find you something perfect I hope you
found this guide To Living in Morgan
point Resort extra helpful it is one of
the most peaceful and beautiful areas
around if you are relocating and have
additional questions on Morgan's Point
Bell County or any of the surrounding
areas you can find all my contact
information below don't forget to
subscribe to my channel so that you can
stay up toate on all things real estate
in Central Texas till next time